Courtney!
I had this sensation of someone
taking my hand, guiding me...
I looked up and I saw this light.
The giant wall of light. Brighter...
All of a sudden, I was in a different place.
Pure energy.
I fail to find words that can describe
what I experienced.
At that point,
I had that out-of-body experience.
I remember a feeling
of being sucked backwards,
like being pulled through water.
I wasn't having thoughts of my own.
Answers, messages coming through me.
Colors were so vivid.
Colors I've never seen before.
Then I was pushed right back into my body.
I could actually see my body from above,
like it was lifeless.
And I was floating up...
Everything I thought was important was
dwarfed by this sense of love.
And I could feel this pull,
a force trying to drag me down
this black tunnel.
Where is it taking me?
I don't know what's going on.
I think I'm going crazy.
I'm seeing things.
Something I did.
I'm sorry.
Hello, Lauren.
How are you feeling?
You had a seizure tonight.
You're at Trinity Emmanuel Medical Center.
Lauren,
do you know that your heart stopped?
You were gone for several minutes,
but the trauma team brought you back.
Do you remember any of that?
If you felt anything, if you saw anything?
Did you lose someone, sweetheart?
She's in here.
We're taking you to Imaging. You'll be okay.
One for transfer in five.
Ready? One, two, three.
Transfer from Holy Cross.
38-year-old construction
worker, fell off a beam.
Persistent coma. GCS 6.
I'll page the resident.
Already done. I got this.
- Which one of you is in charge here?
- It's my intake.
Actually, I'm the one on duty.
I got it. I got it. Thank you.
Standard procedure for a GCS 6 admit
calls for two large-bore IVs
and diazepam on standby.
Seizure meds won't do any good.
Whatever is wrong is
in his spinal column, not his brain.
And what medical protocol are you citing?
The protocol of actually living
in the real world,
where guys with crappy HMOs
go undiagnosed for spinal injuries.
Actually, he's on seizure meds,
which is the medical protocol
of reading his chart.
Shit. No, no, no.
- Shit.
- What is it?
Respiratory failure.
He might be hemorrhaging.
Page Neurosurgery, call a code,
and get CT on standby.
Students, clear the room.
Hey. What is it? What's wrong?
Did you know that there's 12 pairs of nerves
just within the cranial area?
The oculomotor, the trochlear,
the glossopharyngeal, and...
Nine others whose names I cannot remember.
I cannot absorb any more terminology.
I have, like, a rash on my arm.
I can't sleep.
You know, my mother invested
her entire life savings into my education.
Come on.
Come on, that's enough suffering
for one night.
Let's get out of here. Yeah?
It's cold.
We used to be friends, right?
- What is...
- Like, our first year,
when we would sit together at lecture.
Remember?
And we'd, like, go running and get coffee.
Hang out. Do stuff.
We're still friends, though.
No, we don't talk.
We just work and compete.
Who's the fastest to make
a diagnosis of Bell's palsy?
Quick, what's the seven
side effects of Ativan?
You know, just last week,
a second-year committed suicide.
God, Court, you're gonna be
such a good doctor.
Medicine just, like, comes easy to you.
You know, I think there's a way that
we could spend more time together.
- What do you mean?
- Well, I'm just wondering
if you'd help me on this little, like,
extracurricular project I've been working on.
We have neuro shelf exams in, like, 10 days.
I don't really feel like I'm gonna make it.
Oh, Once One Takes The Anatomy Final,
Very Good Vacations Are Heavenly.
- What?
- It's a mnemonic phrase.
You use it to remember the 12 cranial nerves.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
But, yeah, I really would love your help.
Maybe.
Hey.
What's in those?
First one's Mountain Dew laced with Adderall.
Other's a chaser of espressos.
- Together, it's a liquid heart attack.
- Hey, Jamie.
Jesus.
Hey.
"Hey, Jamie." Where were you last night?
Your eyes are still dilated.
25-year-old female, admitted last night.
Complaining of numbness on left side,
nausea, vomiting.
Anything of note from the physical exam?
Sees the color red differently between
left and right eye, and oral ulcers.
Sophia, what test should we run?
A lumbar puncture, then MRI of the brain.
Fine, but reverse the order.
Images first, then procedure.
Preliminary diagnosis, Brad.
- Pituitary cyst?
- No.
Jamie.
Jackie.
- Stroke?
- My God.
You need to do better than this.
All of you.
What do you think the largest
age demographic is in our society today?
You.
Young adults in their 20s, which means
that there are at least 1,000 people waiting
to take your spot.
And we are not in the business of
training country club doctors,
nor do we waste our time
on students who think
that they can skate by
doing the least work necessary.
We are here to educate students
who push themselves,
those who are capable
of making new discoveries
and actually move the dial
on human knowledge.
And for those of you who think
that's too much,
then you should leave.
And by that, I mean now.
Marlo, if I were to tell you
that the patient's family
background was Mediterranean,
i.e., Greek or Turkish,
what would the diagnosis be?
I don't think you'll find it
in your notebook.
It's Behcet's disease.
Thank you, Ray.
Moving on.
Why are you working this event?
You're a trust-fund kid.
You sleep on a sailboat.
Yeah, but there's this really hot caterer
I've been trying to meet.
Look at all these stodgy
old docs with their white wine
and their golf games.
I don't think it's such a bad life.
I don't know about you,
but I'm certainly not gonna spend
the next 40 years doing prostate exams.
No one pays their dues anymore.
Our generation,
it's all about entrepreneurship.
Yeah, so what are you gonna do?
I'm going to LA.
Look at this face.
I'm gonna be the Anderson Cooper
of celebrity medicine.
Okay.
"Hi, Mom. It's my afternoon check-in."
That's funny. Cool. Okay.
You know there's nothing
I can do about her right now.
Did she really move here
just to keep tabs on you?
Hey, come on, look.
- My station is full.
- Okay.
You're so behind.
Okay, sir, got to give you a testicular exam.
- Should just take a minute.
- What? No.
- Excuse the reach.
- Wait a minute.
I don't enjoy it either.
Just close your eyes and pretend
I'm the candy-stripe girl.
What? Get, get the hell off of me!
Hold on.
- Candy-stripe girl.
- Get...
- No, wait a minute.
- Stop! What are you doing?
He doesn't need a testicular exam.
He doesn't?
Come near me again, and I'm killing you.
You know, I think I got mixed up.
It says here the resident wanted a neural
test for that guy, not a testicular exam.
I can't imagine how I passed
the wrong information to you.
Very funny.
Ray can be a real dick sometimes.
You guys notice that?
I think he's intriguing.
Let's go, people. No lunch break today.
Every bed in the unit is full,
and we got referrals waiting in the ER.
Get moving on afternoon rounds.
Excuse me.
Do you have plans tonight?
First-years are having a wingding.
Dorm punch and a deejay,
but I'm not above it.
I can't wait for the anesthesia rotation.
Those guys have access to the best drugs.
Looking for this?
Hell yeah.
I found it on my nightstand.
See you later.
These second-years have no tact,
coming up to me like that
in front of my colleague.
Yeah, we're colleagues, aren't we?
I mean, we have fun together.
Yeah, kinda.
Do you want to have fun with me later?
Courtney Holmes, I am mildly surprised
to be having this conversation with you.
But offer accepted.
Midnight, basement, sub level C.
You want to meet me in the basement?
Sublevel C, underneath the old building.
And take the service elevator,
'cause it doesn't have surveillance cameras.
Yeah. Good idea.
No.
Jesus!
You're late.
What are we doing down here?
Come on, we don't have much time.
Okay, Courtney, what's going on?
It's past midnight. I should be studying.
We're almost there, okay?
What is all of this?
They put this in five years ago.
In case of a natural disaster, loss of power.
It's a fully functioning hospital,
and it never gets used.
Court, what exactly are you up to?
Two of you.
Jamie, what are you doing here?
She didn't tell me about you either, okay?
But, I'm open to a three-way.
Shut up.
What?
I like it.
Scanners, cameras, our choice of beds.
- We can be as loud as we want.
- Courtney, what's going on?
I asked for his help, too.
He probably misinterpreted.
You mean we're not getting it on?
Wait, what are you talking about?
I've been searching
for the region of the brain
that is responsible
for near-death experiences.
And these are postmortem scans
of patients that have died in this hospital.
Is there any circumstance under which
- you'd have sex with me?
- God, stop.
Look, if the brain is just another organ,
why doesn't it just go dark and shut off
at the moment of death?
You know, why the floating?
Why the white light?
Why the sense of well-being?
I mean, what is that experience?
Is it chemical, or is it something else?
Can we map that process
the way we map a seizure?
What if we could actually document
what happens to us after we die?
What do you mean?
Nothing happens. We're dead.
What if we could prove otherwise?
Can you imagine
the residency offers you would get?
And forget about Dr. Oz.
I mean, you would be the world's
first specialist in the afterlife.
Okay, you got my attention.
Come on. This isn't science.
This is pseudoscience.
Well, maybe. Maybe not.
But the only way to find out
is to see for ourselves.
So I would like you both to stop my heart.
Look, I'll be in the imaging scanner.
It will take real-time pictures
of my brain's hemodynamic activity.
You give it one minute,
and then you bring me back.
Wait, you're serious?
- Stop your heart?
- This is propofol.
Fifty milligrams will knock me out.
I'll be wrapped in a cooling blanket,
bringing my core body temperature
down to 86 degrees.
And once that happens,
you administer a defibrillator shock
to stop my heart.
Wait a sec.
Look, I've signed a release. It's in my bag.
It absolves you both of any responsibility.
Courtney, think about what
you're saying right now.
Hey. Look, if she's insane enough to
try it, who are we to stop her?
Look, I'm young, okay?
I'm in excellent health.
You're both trained in emergency medicine.
So reviving me should be
very straightforward.
Look, it's 12:18 now.
I've checked the schedules
for security down here
and cleaning crews.
We have about 45 minutes,
so we should probably get going.
What? This is crazy.
No, count me out of this.
I am not helping you kill yourself.
Well, then you can stand by the door
and make sure nobody comes in.
Okay, remember, there's a magnet
in the scanner,
so no keys or metal in the room.
Look, we've got it.
Wait, Jamie,
what if you can't bring her back?
Then we burn her body, work out our alibi,
and pretend like nothing happened.
And make sure that the scanner's recording,
because if not,
then this whole exercise is pointless.
We're good to go.
Repeat back to me
the resuscitation procedure.
As soon as you're dead, I'll run the scanner.
At 60 seconds, I'll start pulling you out
by switching to the heating blanket.
When your core temp's back up
to 93 degrees, I'll start CPR.
Crash cart is standing by
with the epi and the defib.
Hello? Brain damage. You'll get brain damage.
Not if you resuscitate me in time.
Brain cells can survive without oxygen
for at least four minutes.
Okay.
Now is the point
where you say it's all a joke.
Okay, put the blanket on me.
Jamie, look at her. Come on, she's terrified.
It's just my body's
natural survival instincts.
I anticipated this.
I'm trying to block it out.
Okay.
And now I kill you.
Come on, you'll both get expelled.
You'll go to prison.
Only if you blab about it.
Okay. We're really doing this.
See you later.
She's out.
Body temp's dropping.
Okay, look, Jamie,
we can stop right here, okay?
She sleeps it off, wakes up, and we just
pretend that we followed through with it.
If you can't handle this, then look away.
Fine. Yeah, Jamie, I'll just leave!
- Charging 200.
- Come on! This is wrong!
- Weren't you leaving?
- You're murdering somebody!
Yeah, I probably should've stayed in tonight.
Clear!
Oh, my God.
- She's...
- Dead.
I think.
Counting off 60 seconds.
Do you see any brain activity?
I mean, something's going on,
I'm not really sure what.
It's recording, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah.
- Fifty-one, 52...
- Fifty-three...
Fifty-four, 55, 56, 57,
fifty-eight, 59,
- sixty seconds.
- Get her out.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Blanket's warming.
- What's her temp need to get to again?
- Doesn't matter. Hurry up.
Calm down.
- Charge 200.
- Wait!
Clear!
It's not working.
Of course it isn't.
Paddles are useless without a heart rhythm.
Didn't you listen to her?
Yeah, I was gonna write down all the steps...
Move! Just move.
Move!
Did we order an MRI on... Hey.
- Wait, what are you doing?
- I...
No, she needs an epi.
IV, you moron. God, it's already set up.
Just push the drug into the goddamn arm!
Calm down! I got this.
God.
It's not working. Try something else!
There is nothing else.
Well, I...
What the fuck?
It was an experiment.
She had us stop her heart,
and we can't get her back.
- How long has she been out?
- I don't know, a couple of minutes.
Look, I say we try the paddles.
No, no! Wait! Put them down.
I... Stop, stop.
Take over for Sophia
on the chest compressions.
Do them much harder,
get on top of her if it helps.
Sophia, put that cooling blanket on.
She's too warm.
Then charge the defib
all the way to 360 and stand by.
As soon as Jamie and I get you a heartbeat,
however fluttering,
you put those paddles on her
and give her full power.
The blanket. Come on.
Got to push a lot more epi
than what you've been doing.
Don't stop. Don't stop. Keep going.
All right.
Come on, Courtney.
She's hypoxic.
We need to intubate.
All right? Go!
Let's get it off.
Help me.
BVM.
All right.
Go, go, go, go.
Clear!
Courtney, can you hear me?
You're crazy, you know that?
- You called Ray?
- Were you getting it done?
Does somebody want to fill me in here?
It happened very gently.
Like, almost like an untethering.
And I floated to the ceiling.
I could see my body.
I could see Sophia and Jamie.
And then I could see
the roof of the hospital.
And I've never been up there.
How do you explain that?
I can't explain it.
Are you mad at us?
I don't know what to think
other than you're all pretty stupid.
She's lucky to be alive.
She's alive because of you.
What else happened?
Did you see a white light?
I wouldn't call it that. It was...
It was more like...
Pure energy.
And honestly,
it was kind of sexual, actually.
It was kind of sexual.
Guys, playback's ready.
Hey. Check this out.
Okay, look. We're counting up
from zero at the moment of death.
Cognitive activity has ceased.
Your heart stopped. No breathing, no pulse.
We're 15 seconds in, and there.
Look at that.
Like a bolt of lightning
in your prefrontal cortex.
We might just be witnessing
the afterlife, people.
Okay.
Who knows what we're looking at?
We're not radiologists.
I mean, it could just be
residual electricity.
- You know, synapses shutting down.
- Okay, we're moving on.
So, you've been dead almost 40 seconds now,
and look.
This area lights up, the hippocampus.
- That's not the hippocampus.
- Of course it is.
That is the ventral tegmental area.
It's the oldest part of the brain,
governs thirst, hunger, love.
Okay, doctors, I'm glad you're having fun.
Got to get out of here.
Hey, Ray, come on.
Hey, no. Just let him go.
It's over. Her brain's just dark now.
- No.
- Look at that.
Wait. Amygdala.
That's the amygdala. Rage.
Stress. Emotional memory.
Whatever you were seeing,
this is just before we pulled you out.
Is she okay?
She's been sitting there
for, like, 10 minutes.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What do you think she's doing out there?
I hope she doesn't try to fly.
If there were brain chemicals released,
the aftereffects could still be
in her bloodstream.
I took LSD once.
I stayed awake for three days.
Shit.
I'm gonna go check on her.
Let's leave.
That's high.
Hey.
Are you okay?
I'm gonna bake some bread.
What's with the bread?
Courtney baked it. Six loaves, last night.
She remembered her grandmother's recipe.
Also, she ran 12 miles.
- Twelve miles?
- Let's begin.
We've been ramping up Michael Evergreen
with meds for ten hours,
and his epilepsy hasn't gotten any better.
Now he's developed a skin rash.
It's a mystery. The meds should be working.
Carbamazepine?
What?
Carbamazepine has an 11% chance
of reacting negatively
with lamotrigine, which is the other drug
- that Michael's on.
- Seriously?
Good catch, Courtney.
Sophia, next case.
Adele Gunther. 44 years old.
Admitted with mild confusion.
Says her sister's an impostor,
she doesn't recognize her.
No history of trauma. Too young for dementia.
We're gonna send it out to Psychiatry for...
It's Capgras syndrome.
- Go on.
- Capgras is an impairment
of the brain's facial recognition center.
And a very rare diagnosis.
V.S. Ramachandran, in his book,
Phantoms of the Brain,
links frontal cortex dichotomies,
like this, to Capgras.
That's not on this year's syllabus.
Optional reading in my first year.
Well, that's more like it.
My sister loved this piece.
Drug warnings for carbamazepine
run 20 pages long.
How could she possibly
recall a detail like that?
How is she playing the piano again,
after 12 years?
She's not playing that well.
It's like her brain's been rewired,
accessing everything she's ever learned.
I don't care what happened to her.
This experiment needs to end right now.
I'm not gonna risk everything
for a morbid fascination you guys have.
You think you're all medical pioneers?
You're just a bunch of
rich kids screwing around,
before you become wealthy specialists
with your Ivy League bumper stickers
on your Mercedes.
I was with you until the end.
No one puts bumper stickers on a Mercedes.
I think we're way past parlor tricks here.
That does it. I'm going next.
- Okay.
- Tonight. I am.
And you're all gonna be there.
It's a good day to die.
No! No!
Jesus Christ.
Is that what I looked like?
Yep. Exactly like that.
- I knew you'd show up.
- How long has he been under?
Forty-five seconds.
I thought you'd had it
with all this foolishness.
Jamie asked me to be here.
He wanted me to pull him out.
- Pause compressions.
- One, two, three...
- Still no heartbeat.
- Pushing epi.
- Come on, Jamie, wake up.
- He can't hear you.
Sophia, get ready to intubate.
Okay. I've never done this before,
- so just give me a second...
- Just do it!
Ray, relax. There's no need to panic.
Let's give the epi a second to work.
Jamie...
Clear!
Take it out, take it out.
Hey...
Jamie, Jamie, Jamie.
I need a drink.
Shots, shots, shots!
Yeah, come on.
- Cheers!
What do you guys think about
taking this wall down?
- No, no, no.
- I've always wanted a loft.
It's hailing! Courtney!
What?
Watch it.
This is crazy.
It's like they're on the same wavelength.
We should bottle flatlining,
sell it as a club drug.
Here. Use this.
- Hey, no, no.
- No, no, no.
Oh, my God.
This has been the strangest night of my life.
You going next, Ray?
What, flatlining? No way.
I'd bring you back out.
Maybe.
You have to admit, I was pretty good
with that defibrillator.
You were okay.
Would it kill you to admit that
I might be just as good a doctor as you?
I never said you were not.
Hey, Marlo, your brother's here.
You have no more experience
than the rest of us.
I do.
I was a firefighter in Houston.
Almost six years.
I'm going next.
It was super fun.
I was all-powerful.
I had the whole city to myself.
It's weird, isn't it?
I thought there'd be more people, like...
Aren't you supposed to see...
Family members who've died, or...
Maybe there's no one there
because it wasn't really our time.
Was it all fun?
What do you mean?
I don't... I mean, like,
was there anything disturbing or...
Not really.
Why?
Nothing.
She's stabilizing.
I don't understand,
the data shows her starting
into a massive seizure,
and then it just went away.
I gave her Ativan.
On whose authority?
I'm sorry. I'll get approval next time.
You saved her life.
Yes, I did.
I'm Jesus.
Everyone I touch today, I'm gonna heal.
You know, it's funny,
because you and Courtney both flat...
You both flatlined,
yet Courtney is focused on the past,
memories, recipes.
Whereas you, you're focused on
the present, using your intuition.
What does that have in common with Courtney?
Sophia, Marlo, you're needed in the ICU.
It's an awakening.
See you later, Jesus.
- An awakening?
- Yeah.
You here for the abortion?
Should Ernesto La Paz get morphine?
I'll check with the resident.
Sophia? Where are you going?
It's 11:30 at night.
You're not on call,
and you don't have anything scheduled.
No, I'm going to the library.
I'm just gonna do some more studying.
No, no, no, no.
I'm making tea,
and we're gonna start reviewing
all of the terminology
for the nervous system.
- But I...
- Now.
Okay.
Where's Sophia?
We need to start. It's already 12:15.
This isn't gonna hurt, is it?
The anesthesia will take care of that.
Three minutes.
Well, Jamie only did two.
What can I say?
I'm competitive.
After my three minutes are done,
these are the interventions I want,
in their specific order.
If I don't come out right away,
I want you to intubate me.
Force the oxygen, okay?
Hey, I'm gonna bring you out of it.
Relax. Enjoy the experience.
Okay, okay.
Infusion's flowing.
She's out. Body temp's 94.
Charging 200.
Clear.
Asystole.
38-year-old male,
stung in the face by a jellyfish.
...by a jellyfish.
That's it. Let's get her out.
Epi in.
- Defib!
- Charge to 200.
Clear.
- No pulse.
- Damn it, we just had it.
Juice her again.
I'm gonna push an epi and sodium bicarb.
Defib. She's not stabilizing.
Charge 300.
Clear. Come on.
No pulse.
This is not working. I need to intubate.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey, hey.
Calm down. I got this.
360. Clear.
Please.
She's back.
You good? You're all right.
- Yeah.
- There you go.
We're safe. No one ever comes up here.
- It's so beautiful.
- Isn't it?
Her temp's low.
Pulse still racing.
Well, I think three minutes is too long.
Look, she had a bad trip, it happens.
What, you're an expert?
Yeah, more than you.
- Is she okay?
- Where have you been?
- Marlo is fine.
- Yeah, I'll be okay.
I'm going next. Right now.
- Right now?
- Why not?
The cleaning crew is gonna be
down there in like 20 minutes.
- Okay.
- No, we've gone too far.
No more flatlining.
Okay, so you three get to
expand your consciousness
and get academic advantage, but I don't?
Advantage.
You think this makes you better, Sophia?
This makes you dead.
You have much more sense than that.
Ray, if this bothers you so much,
then just walk away.
- Well, maybe I should.
- You're not going anywhere.
You're in this as deep as the rest of us.
Okay, look,
I don't care how dangerous this is.
I need this more than any of you guys.
Ray, it's her decision.
Just like it was each of ours.
If Sophia wants to do this,
then we're doing it tonight.
Just don't stay in too long.
A B-plus on a biology exam is not acceptable.
Not acceptable.
That will not get you into
a top-10 medical school.
Someone's coming down the elevator.
- What?
- Get her out.
Come on, come on, come on.
Let's go. Let's go!
Pushing an amp of epi.
Where the hell are you going?
Start compressions.
Please, God, bring her back.
Good thinking, Doctor.
I'm sure that's gonna help.
Epi in.
Pause compressions.
Clear.
Irina.
You are not the only kid
that is out there trying to get in.
Shit.
One, two, three.
- V-tach.
- Charging 360.
Clear.
We got her, we got her.
Let's go, let's go. Come on.
We're gonna get you out of here.
You're gonna be okay.
- Come on, you'll be okay. Come here.
- Come on.
- Come on!
- I got her, I got her.
- My jacket, my jacket.
- Got it.
Go, go.
Okay. To the right.
It's open. Just get in.
- Okay.
- Okay, okay.
Should you really be driving?
Wait!
Shit!
You asshole! You left us.
- Are you okay?
- The hell I did.
- I saved your asses.
- Let's go!
- Here they come!
- Hold it right there!
We got to get out of here!
Hold on!
We're going too fast!
Oh, my God.
- Shit!
- Car!
God!
Watch out!
Oh, my God!
It's not funny.
Here we go.
Where are we going?
Hell yeah.
Courtney!
Come.
Look, I don't know if it's the experience
of dying and coming back again,
but I have got a really
intense craving right now.
For what, gelato?
No.
Oh, my God, this is crazy!
Sophia.
Sophia, open this door!
I think there's someone at the door.
- Sophia!
- I don't care.
Don't stop.
Sophia, I need you to open this door.
Sophia!
It's nice to meet you, Mrs. Manning.
How dare you bring someone
back to my apartment.
I'm moving out.
- What did you say?
- I'm finding my own place.
You will do no such thing.
See, it doesn't matter what you say, Mom.
Whatever threats you make. I'm 25 years old.
Succeed or fail...
I'm doing it on my own.
Good night.
All right.
How are you getting home?
There's a metro stop nearby.
Look, there's something I need to tell you.
It's important.
So, you gonna tell me or what?
I killed someone.
What?
It was two months ago.
It was my ER rotation.
The patient's name was Cyrus Gudgeon.
He was admitted for a jellyfish sting.
Cyrus Gudgeon. Yeah, I remember.
He got stung in the face.
Died of shock, right?
No, he died because of a mistake that I made.
I gave him epi and Benadryl.
But those two drugs don't cross-react.
He had metoprolol in his system.
He basically suffocated to death.
I'd been on duty for, like, 36 hours,
and I must have screwed up
and forgotten to ask him
if he was taking any medications.
He would be alive right now
if it wasn't for my mistake.
Why are you telling me this?
Because I saw him.
Cyrus. I saw him in my flatline.
And it must mean something, right?
Hey, mistakes happen to everybody.
Yeah, but I work so hard every single day.
- I do the right thing.
- I'm sure you do.
- I'm not a bad person.
- No, you're not.
I'm not a bad person. I...
- Everything's gonna be fine, Marlo.
- No, I'm scared.
I'm scared.
Wait, wait, wait.
You... You can't just...
I'm... I'm sorry.
Yeah, what am I doing with you?
- I got to go right now. I'm sorry. No...
- No. No, no, no, wait.
- Damn, you have so many.
- Just...
Okay, okay.
I got it, I got it.
Courtney!
Help!
Help! Tessa!
Tessa!
Help!
My sister!
- My sister.
- Come on.
No! My sister!
Tessa! My... Tessa!
No!
I hope this doesn't become awkward.
Too late.
I can't imagine what you must think of me.
Why?
Well, first I tell you that I'm responsible
for the death of a patient,
and then I go and totally attack you.
I mean, seriously, what...
What do you see in me?
You're really hot.
Shut up.
I got to go.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It was four months into our first year.
You were assisting at the oncology ward.
A breast cancer patient was there
for her first round of chemo.
She was anxious and scared,
but you sat down and calmed her
by asking about her kids, her job.
You were so kind.
You didn't think anyone was watching,
but I was watching you through the door.
Three hours later, I stopped by,
and you were there checking on her again.
That's what I see in you.
Jamie?
Courtney? What's going on?
I saw my sister.
What?
At the waterfront.
It was her.
I saw my dead sister.
Where... Where are you?
I'm home.
I don't understand what's happening.
Stay there.
I'm coming over.
I just... I miss my sister.
I should have told you all that
this wasn't about
science or discovery.
I think I'm going crazy.
Like I'm seeing things.
Something I did.
It was my fault.
I'm sorry.
Tessa?
Tessa, is that really you?
Tessa, are you okay?
- What are you?
- Courtney!
Courtney!
Let's go!
Hi. An update on room four.
We've given the Lasix bolus,
and the output is limited.
It's been less than 50 cc's
in the last two hours.
All right.
They found her at
the bottom of a fire escape.
We'll know more after the autopsy,
but right now, it's unclear whether she fell,
jumped, or God knows what.
I know you all liked her.
And I'm sorry, but for now, I need you
to pick up her patient load
and divide it amongst yourselves.
We still have a hospital to run.
Do any of you know what might
have been going on with her?
Is there something you're not telling me?
All right.
It just doesn't feel real.
I know.
You know, I can't believe she's gone.
We need to talk.
Okay, something is happening to us,
and my mind is playing tricks on me.
This morning,
when I was swimming in the pool...
I can't talk, okay?
- I have rounds right now.
- Guys,
Wolfson already knows
we're holding something back.
The school is going to investigate her death.
I don't believe it was a suicide.
Maybe she fell.
You were there.
What happened?
She never answered the door.
I figured... She went to bed.
Hey, killer party?
You all look like shit.
Hey, listen,
if the school finds out
we have been flatlining,
we will be expelled.
And you can say goodbye to your future.
Any notes you've taken, destroy them.
I'm gonna get into Courtney's apartment,
get her phone, computer,
anything incriminating.
You know, you were right
this whole time, Ray.
We should've listened to you.
Yeah, that's true.
This isn't on you, man.
You should just walk away.
We'll keep your name out of it.
No.
I'm not going anywhere.
Whatever happens to all of you happens to me.
- Yes?
- Hey.
Look, bad news.
Ray and I checked her apartment.
We found her computer and some notes,
- but not her phone.
- Campus security
- could have gotten there before you.
- Okay.
Assuming you're right
and it's not a criminal investigation,
then all that stuff stays with her body.
Meaning you can go down there
and look for it.
Go down where?
Where do you think? The goddamn morgue.
Okay.
Marlo.
Marlo?
Jamie...
Jamie.
Like I'm seeing things.
Something I did.
It was my fault.
I'm sorry.
Tessa?
Tessa, is that really you?
Are you okay?
What are you?
Jesus Christ.
What was that?
She was talking to someone.
Someone was there.
You don't know that.
She could've been hallucinating.
It didn't sound like that to me.
What if it was Tessa?
What do you mean?
She saw something. You heard her.
She said that she did something.
Something was her fault.
What if that's it? What if...
What if our sins are coming for us?
Sins. That's ridiculous.
So, what are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna tell each other
the goddamn truth.
That's what we're gonna do.
There's a girl I... I used to know.
Alicia.
She was a waitress at my dad's country club.
Oh, my God.
- You killed her?
- What? No.
No, I did not kill anyone.
I...
I... I...
I got her pregnant.
I wanted to help, you know?
Pay for the abortion, be...
Go with her for the procedure.
Anyway, the... The day came,
and I... I couldn't deal with it.
I... I drove right past.
I left her to fend for herself.
And she showed up in your flatline?
I wish that was all.
She showed up last night, too.
So you're being haunted
by somebody that's alive.
- What are you talking about?
- This.
I am talking about this.
Alicia did this to me.
Only it wasn't her.
Just like it wasn't Courtney's sister.
Then what was it?
Jamie, what?
I... I don't know.
Something feeding off our guilty conscience.
What do you mean? Like...
Something demonic?
Maybe it's using our pasts, our sins.
Wait, wait.
We're rational people here.
You could have stabbed yourself.
People on drugs hurt themselves all the time.
There has to be a logical explanation.
I was 17.
Her name was Irina Wong,
and she had a higher GPA than I did,
so I hacked her text messages
and I sent her naked photos
to the whole class.
It destroyed her.
What is the point in confessing all of this?
This is clearly just happening here.
- That thing...
- Look, look, Courtney said to me
she thinks maybe we opened a door.
Wait, so you knew?
You and Courtney knew there was
a downside to flatlining,
and... And you still let me and Marlo go in?
Hey, look, I thought it was
just part of the experience.
Side effects may include dry mouth,
hallucinations, existential dread.
I did not know that
the side effects would show up
and start hunting us down.
There is a scientific explanation
to all of this.
We're way beyond explanations.
Okay.
If Courtney was right,
whatever's happening to us,
these hallucinations, these hauntings,
whatever it is,
it's only gonna get worse.
Until we figure it out,
until we figure out what to do,
whatever killed her
is gonna kill all of us, too.
Note the negative mass effect
secondary to the encephalomalacia.
There are multiple foci of high
T2 and FLAIR signal intensity
in the supratentorial white matter.
These findings are nonspecific,
but most in keeping with
chronic microangiopathic changes.
You'll note there's no hydrocephalus.
There's no brain herniation.
The vessels are well seen.
You'll note that the gray matter
differentiation is completely maintained.
You little slut.
I can't believe you slept with him.
Not only are you a hopeless grind,
but you're an immature,
whiney, crybaby bitch.
- Okay, stop!
- Excuse me?
Sorry. Sorry.
No.
No! No! No!
No!
No.
Stop!
Stop! No!
No!
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Have you seen Cyrus Gudgeon lately?
If that's supposed to be a joke,
- it's not funny.
- It's not a joke.
Then what?
I pulled the autopsy report.
It says nothing about metoprolol.
So then I went back to the original
path lab notes of the blood test,
and there it was.
Metoprolol.
I'm going inside.
Why wouldn't the autopsy report
match with the notes, Marlo?
Marlo?
Marlo.
Did you change that autopsy report?
I had to protect myself.
Protect yourself? Really?
By making it look like he died from a sting
and not a drug you administered?
I know.
- I know. It was wrong of me.
- You got to tell someone.
- I am. I'm telling you.
- The dean, Marlo.
You have to tell the dean
you changed that report.
Why?
- What good is that gonna do now?
- Really?
You don't see it?
It's your flatline, Cyrus Gudgeon.
You know, it was so nice being with you
and realizing, after all this time,
that you actually like me.
And now you have to go and spoil it.
- I am here because I like you.
- Yeah, well, it's easy for you.
You don't have to sacrifice anything.
I'm becoming a doctor
with a degree from a top medical school.
I've worked my whole life for this.
And now, I... I made one mistake.
I mean, admitting it
is not gonna bring the guy back.
All it's gonna do is end my career.
That is the point here,
your career.
If you were willing to change
an autopsy report, then...
Say it.
Then maybe you shouldn't be a doctor.
Hi. Is this Beverly Wong?
Beverly Wong from East Hadley?
It is?
Do you have a daughter named Irina?
Hey.
Thanks for coming with me.
Could you have rented a smaller car?
You're sure it's the same Irina?
Irina.
Yes.
It's Sophia.
From East Hadley.
We went to the same high school.
I'm sorry. I know, it... It's...
It's been forever.
I...
I really needed to talk to you,
so I was hoping we could sit down...
What is this about?
You never knew this, but...
I was the one who sent your pictures
to the whole class.
That was me.
I can't stand myself to think about it.
Bottom line, it was
an awful thing to do. I know that.
What do you want?
I'd like you to accept my apology.
It's not necessary.
Okay? I've moved on.
Irina... This is important, okay?
I am so sorry.
Irina, please.
Sophia.
I forgive you.
Thank you.
What'd she say?
Hey, Marlo, it's Jamie.
- Hey.
- Look, we're just kind of riffing here,
but maybe you find whoever you've wronged,
whatever you're feeling guilty about,
and you take responsibility.
I mean, look, who knows if it'll work?
But what have we got to lose?
Alicia!
Alicia.
Hey. It's... It's me.
It's Jamie.
What are you doing here, Jamie?
He's your son?
Hey. Hey... I came to apologize.
For taking off on you.
I... I panicked. I was a coward.
I should have been there for you.
But you weren't.
Look, I...
I want to make amends.
Do what's right.
Help... Help you out.
Whatever you need.
Alicia.
Who is that man, Mommy?
What?
What the hell?
Sophia?
I just got a message from Marlo.
Something's wrong. And her phone is off.
We need to find her.
Okay. Where are you?
I'm... I'm gonna come to you.
Marlo?
Marlo!
She's not here, man.
Wait. Wait!
Marlo?
Forget it. She's here.
Come as fast as you can!
I'm nearly there.
You got to hurry.
Ray!
She must be down there. Come.
Okay.
Come on!
- Oh, my God.
- No, no, no, no, no!
Oh, my God. How long has she been under?
It's been over four minutes.
- BVM?
- Sure.
Come on. We need oxygen!
Cyrus. I'm so sorry.
Forgive me.
Will you please forgive me?
No pulse.
Take over the compressions.
Go, go, go!
It's not working. Shit.
Stop.
Nothing.
Ray.
Marlo, don't you get it?
I need you to come back.
To me.
Marlo, Marlo...
Marlo? Marlo.
No! No!
Marlo.
You have to forgive yourself.
Forgive yourself, Marlo.
No!
Charge 360.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my...
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey.
Here.
There you go.
Thank you.
You okay?
Yeah.
I found the girl.
And a little boy.
Yeah.
The hell with going to L.A.
I'm getting a residency right here.
Be near them.
I'm gonna try.
Courtney was right.
It's not enough to apologize.
We have to face up to what we've done,
and then forgive ourselves.
Some lines should not be crossed.
We lost a friend.
We will never be the same.
Where were you?
I talked to the dean.
How'd it go?
I'm on probation.
Did you bring it?
Here.
Only Courtney knows now.
Feels so weird just being here
without Courtney.
Anyone want to say something?
Let's just get hammered.
Why don't you say something?
To Courtney.